(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
桃鈴ねね
Momosuzu Nene
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
オトメロディー
作詞：山田ひろし 作曲：渡部チェル
Otome Melody
Lyrics: Hiroshi Yamada Composition: Cher Watanabe
スキスキッスー
I love, love, love you
フワフワフー
Fluffy, fluffy, fluff
こんなキモチ
A feeling like this
メロメロディ
Mero-melody
夢だけど
It's a dream, but
夢じゃない
it's not a dream
お願いね
Please,
マイメロディ
My Melody
オトナじゃない
I'm not an adult,
乙女です
I'm a maiden
恋するのが仕事です
Falling in love is my job
君の名前つぶやくと
When I whisper your name
ドキドキするの
My heart starts pounding
聞き分けない
This heart of mine
この胸が
that won't listen,
歌い出した
has started to sing
止まらない
It won't stop
上手じゃなくてごめんなさい
I'm sorry I'm not very good at it
だけど聞いて
But please listen
届け マイメロディ
Reach out, my melody
マイメロディ
My melody
星空を越えて
Across the starry sky
君の夢 守るリボン
The ribbon that protects your dreams
マイメロディ
My melody
ハート見つけたら
Once I find your heart
ぐるぐる巻きしちゃうからね
I'll wrap it up tight
WOW WOW WOW
覚悟しといて
Be prepared
嘘じゃない
It's not a lie
大人じゃない 乙女です
I'm not an adult, I'm a maiden
泣いたりだってしちゃいます
I even cry sometimes
女の子って魔法で
Girls are made of magic
つくられたの
That's how we were created
スキスキス
Love love love
ふわふわふ
Fluffy fluffy fluffy
こんな気持ち メロメロディ
These feelings are melo-melody
夢だけど
It's a dream, but...
夢じゃない
...it's not a dream
お願いね マイメロディ
Please, my melody
キライじゃない ていうかスキ
I don't hate you, in fact, I love you
スナオになんてなれません
I just can't be honest with myself
君の笑顔 見るだけで
Just by seeing your smile
ふにゃふにゃするの
I turn to mush
それなのに それなのに
And yet, and yet...
憎まれ口 撃ちまくり
I keep shooting off my mouth
ひとりになって落ち込んで
Then I get lonely and depressed
マクラパンチ
And punch my pillow
だから マイメロディ
That's why, my melody
マイメロディ
My melody
本当の気持ち 風になって
Let my true feelings become the wind
結ぶリボン
And tie a ribbon
マイメロディ
My melody
歌え 乙女ゴコロ
Sing out, a maiden's heart
くるくる恋 捕まえちゃえ
Catch that swirling love
WOW WOW WOW
逃がさないから
I won't let you get away
ここへ来て
Come over here
キライじゃない つらいです
I don't hate you, it's painful
真っ赤にだってなっちゃいます
I even turn bright red
女の子って不思議で
Girls are mysterious
つくられたの
That's how we were created
届け マイメロディ
Reach out, my melody
マイメロディ
My melody
星空を越えて
Across the starry sky
君の夢 守るリボン
The ribbon that protects your dreams
マイメロディ
My melody
ハート見つけたら
Once I find your heart
ぐるぐる巻きしちゃうからね
I'll wrap it up tight
WOW WOW WOW
覚悟しといて
Be prepared
嘘じゃない
It's not a lie
大人じゃない 乙女です
I'm not an adult, I'm a maiden
泣いたりだってしちゃいます
I even cry sometimes
女の子って魔法で
Girls are made of magic
つくられたの
That's how we were created
スキスキス
Love love love
ふわふわふ
Fluffy fluffy fluffy
こんな気持ち メロメロディ
These feelings are melo-melody
夢だけど
It's a dream, but...
夢じゃない
...it's not a dream
お願いね マイメロディ
Please, my melody
マイメロディ
My melody
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today on, I'll tell you one thing I like about you
1日1個伝えよう
one thing every day
365回 ドキドキさせちゃうぜ
I'll make your heart race 365 times
バッキューン！
Bang!
「こっちにおいでよ」もう
“Come over here,” geez
もしかしてまだ片思い？
Could it be that it's still unrequited love?
「たまに甘えてくるくせに！」
“Even though you come to me for spoiled attention sometimes!”
もしかして転がされてる？
Could it be that I'm being played?
毎日通ってた
I went there every day
君と目が合う度に
Every time our eyes met
恋が爆発
My love exploded
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today on, I'll tell you one thing I like about you
1日1個伝えよう
one thing every day
365回 ドキドキさせちゃうぜ
I'll make your heart race 365 times
バッキューン！
Bang!
他どこ見たり(No! No!)
Looking somewhere else (No! No!)
携帯ばっか見たり(No! No!)
Looking at your phone all the time (No! No!)
君だけ見てるよ えらいのご褒美は？
I'm only looking at you. What's the reward for being good?
チュッ
Smooch
「たまにはお出かけどう？」
“How about going out for a change?”
「いつも部屋デートばかりじゃん？」
“It's always just dates in your room, isn't it?”
もちろんそれでもいいぎ
Of course, even that's fine...
もちろんそれでもいいけど
Of course, that's fine too,
僕だってオシャレしたいし
But I want to dress up too,
気分屋な君
You, who are so moody...
ああ お世話が焼けるな
Ah, you're such a handful.
僕がいないと何も
Without me, you can't...
できないくせに
...do anything.
毎日君の機嫌取って
Every day, I'll keep you happy,
一日いっぱいハグして
And hug you all day long.
何百回何千回
Hundreds, thousands of times,
愛を伝え合おうぜ
Let's tell each other we love each other.
バッキューン！
Bang!
独りにしちゃったり
If I leave you alone,
ゲームばっかりしたり
Or just play games all the time,
君だけ見てるよ
I'll only look at you.
偉いのご褒美は？
What's my reward for being good?
チュッ
Chu!
帰り遅くなりそうだけど
I might be home late,
急いで帰るからね
But I'll hurry back.
寄り道せずに愛の巣
Going straight to our love nest...
ただいまー！
I'm home!
お帰りもナシ？
No "Welcome home"?
よしよしもナシ？
No "There, there" either?
それでもいいよ だから
Even so, it's okay. So...
一緒にいてね
Please stay with me.
ねえねえどこ隠れてるの
Hey, where are you hiding?
もしかして出ていっちゃった？
Did you maybe leave me?
急に飛びついてきた
Suddenly, you jumped on me.
君は小悪魔だね
You're such a little devil.
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today, your favorite parts...
一日一個伝えよう
I'll tell you one every day.
365回
365 times,
ドキドキさせちゃうぜ
I'll make your heart race!
バッキューン！
Bang!
他の子を見たり
Looking at other girls,
携帯ばっかり見たり
Or just looking at your phone...
君だけ見てるよ
I'll only look at you.
偉いのご褒美は？
What's my reward for being good?
チュッ
Chu!
はーい！
Hi!
というわけで今日は、遅めの誕生日ライブということで
And so, today is my belated birthday live...
みんな見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming to see me!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ダンスもね、歌もたくさん頑張ったので
I worked really hard on the dancing and singing,
細かいところまでたくさん注目して見てほしいなって思います。
so I hope you'll pay attention to all the little details.
まぁ、そんなこんなで今2曲ちょうど終わったところなんですけど、
Well, anyway, I've just finished two songs...
「乙女メロディ」と「小悪魔だってかまわない！」でした！
They were "Otome Melody" and "Koakuma Datte Kamawanai!"!
どうでしたか皆さん？
How was it, everyone?
どうでしたか？
How was it?
可愛かった？
Was it cute?
そう、乙女メロディも小悪魔だってかまわないもね、あの、
Yeah, both Otome Melody and Koakuma Datte Kamawanai...
演出がね、ある感じにしたんですけど、
I wanted them to have special staging,
めちゃめちゃ可愛く作ってもらったからね。
and they made it look so cute.
それもね、ちゃんとアーカイブとかでも細かいところまでちゃんと見てほしいですね。
I really want you to check out all the details in the archives too.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
というわけで、イラストの方はどうでしたか？
By the way, how were the illustrations?
みんな気づきましたか？絵が変わってたの。
Did everyone notice the pictures changed?
あ、今はね、これサムネのイラストなんだけど、
Oh, right now, this is the thumbnail illustration,
めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
it's super cute, right?
こうやって、こうやってる。
She's doing this... and this.
めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
Super cute, right?
そう。で、次が「乙女メロディ」のね、イラストなんですけど、
Right. And next is the "Otome Melody" illustration...
え、めっちゃ可愛い。もうこれ、なもり先生がね、
Wow, it's so cute. This one was done by Namori-sensei,
に描いてもらいました。めちゃめちゃ可愛い。
and they drew it for me. It's incredibly cute.
本当に可愛い。うさぎ。
So cute. A bunny.
うさぎです。
It's a bunny.
で、次が「小悪魔だってかまわない」。
And next is "Koakuma Datte Kamawanai".
可愛い。これは、桜ひより先生に描いてもらいました。
Cute! This one was drawn by Sakura Hiyori-sensei.
可愛いね。
It's cute, isn't it?
こんな、こんな小悪魔いたらね、いたずらされてもね、
If a little devil like this existed,
みんな許しちゃうよね。
everyone would forgive her for playing pranks, right?
はい、というわけでこんな感じで、
Alright, so, like this...
他のね、あの、全部のコラボ曲とかも、
all the other collaboration songs,
まだあるソロ曲とかも、イラストがあるから、
and the remaining solo songs also have illustrations,
ぜひね、後ろの画面にもみんな注目して見てください。
so please pay attention to the screen behind me too.
見てねー。
Don't miss it!
というわけで今日はこの後は、ゲスト、ゲスト続きとなっております。
And so, for the rest of today, we have one guest after another.
あんまり3Dで並んだことないゲストをね、ここにいるんだけどね。
We have guests here that I haven't stood next to in 3D very often...
そう、二人で並んだことはないよねーみたいな人を呼んでね、
Yeah, I invited someone where we've never stood side-by-side like this before,
なんか、あれ、ちょっと、よく、よく仲良く、あら、結構、結婚相手もちょっと来てるんですけど、今日は。
and, well, we're quite... close... and actually, my "marriage partner" is also coming today.
はい、そんな感じで、どうぞこの後もコラボ続き、
Right, so with that, please enjoy the upcoming collaborations,
たくさん見てってね。
keep watching!
ずっと見てね。
Keep watching the whole time.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
バーチャルニュース
Virtual News
動物園から熊が脱走！
Bear escapes from zoo!
動物園からクマが脱走。付近の住民は注意を見かけたらすぐに通報！
A bear escaped from the zoo. Residents in the area should be careful and report immediately if they see it!
ニュースから熊が脱走だって？
A bear escaped, according to the news?
シオンも脱走してみたーい。
Shion wants to escape too!
っていうか、もうこんな時間か。
Wait, it's already this late.
早く帰って配信の準備しないと。
I have to go home and prepare for my stream.
うわぁーーー！
Whoa!
熊が歩いて事務所入ってきた！
A bear just walked into the office!
やばい、バレたら食われる！
Oh no, if it finds me, I'll be eaten!
誰かに電話して助けに来てもらわないと。
I have to call someone and have them come save me.
はーい、何ー？
Hi, what's up?
あ、もしもしあくあ？
Ah, hello, Aqua?
今事務所で熊に襲われかけてるんだけど助けに来て！
I'm about to be attacked by a bear in the office, come help me!
へー、熊すごい。
Heh, a bear? That's amazing.
シオン食われるから早く助けに来て！
I'm gonna be eaten, so hurry up and help me!
うーん、後でねー。
Hmm, maybe later.
おっ、あ、後ろにいたんだけど。シールド割れた！
Oh, ah, he was behind me. Cracked his shield!
お前、エペやってんだろ！
You're playing Apex, aren't you?!
ごめん、ちょっと今忙しいからまた後で。
Sorry, I'm a bit busy right now, so catch you later.
切りやがったし。
She hung up on me.
だめだ。早く次の人に電話しよう。
This is bad. Let's call the next person.
そうだ、船長！船長なら助けてくれる！
That's it, Senchou! She'll help me!
年上だし。
She's my senior, after all.
はい、宝鐘です。
Hello, this is Houshou.
船長助けて！
Senchou, help!
今事務所で熊に襲われてるの。シオン食われちゃうよ。
I'm being attacked by a bear in the office. I'm gonna be eaten!
えー、熊？どんな熊？
Ehh, a bear? What kind of bear?
もうヤバいやつ！
A really dangerous one!
目が血走ってて、爪とか牙とか1メートルくらいあって、二足歩行してる！
His eyes are bloodshot, he has claws and fangs like a meter long, and he's walking on two legs!
早く助けに来て船長！
Hurry up and help me, Senchou!
ああ、はいはい。そういう。
Ah, I see. I get it.
まあ、はい。
Well, yeah.
えーと、船長はあんまりリアル系のガチ熊はアウトオブ眼中でして。
Well, real-life grizzly bears aren't really my thing.
ぬいぐるみみたいに可愛いモコモコの熊ちゃんがタイプなんですよね。
I prefer cute, fluffy bears like stuffed animals.
なので、まあ正直ちょっと...
So, to be honest...
興味なーいっす。
I'm not interested.
すんません。じゃ、そういうことで。
Sorry about that. Anyway, see ya.
いや好みとか聞いてないんですけど。通話切れたし。
Hey, I didn't ask about your preferences. She hung up too.
誰も助けに来ないんだけど。
Is no one coming to help me?
シオンとの絆はどこにあんだよ！
What happened to our bonds?!
さ、坂又。坂又か。
S-Sakamata. Sakamata, huh.
まあ、シャチだし、いけるか。
Well, she's an orca, so maybe she can do it.
あ、シオン先輩！今日の配信で...
Ah, Shion-senpai! In today's stream...
坂又助けて！事務所で熊に襲われてるの！
Sakamata, help! I'm being attacked by a bear in the office!
え！？熊！？種類は！？
What?! A bear?! What species?!
知るか！早く助けに来て！
I don't know! Just come help me!
わかりました！待っててください！なる早で向かいます！
Understood! Please wait! I'll be there as fast as I can!
助けに来ました、シオン先輩！
I've come to help you, Shion-senpai!
はやっ！
That was fast!
お前がシオン先輩をいじめる悪い熊か！
So you're the bad bear who's picking on Shion-senpai!
やったれ坂又！ぶちかましてやれ！
Get him, Sakamata! Kick his butt!
シャチなめさせんぞ！
Don't underestimate an orca!
うわああ！俺のシオンから離れろーーー！
Whoa! Get away from my Shion!
うわああ！
Waaaah!
坂又のうでがーーー！
Sakamata's arm is...!
やっぱだめか。
Guess it's no use.
あ、シオン先輩助けてー。
Ah, Shion-senpai, help me.
後輩が体を張っているこの状況で、先輩であるシオンが引き下がるわけにはいかない。
With my junior putting her life on the line like this, I, her senior, can't just back down.
世間体的にも。
Not for my reputation's sake.
こらー！坂又を放せ！
Hey! Let go of Sakamata!
ごめん、やっぱ帰るわ。
Sorry, I'm actually going home.
シオン先輩ーーー！
Shion-senpai!
ねぇねぇ もしものもしもだよ
Hey, hey, just suppose...
私が帰り道 グリズリーに襲われたら
If on my way home, I were attacked by a grizzly bear,
あなたなら どうする？
what would you do?
グリズリーに襲われたら♡
作詞・作曲：清 竜人　編曲：MOSAIC.WAV
When Attacked by a Grizzly♡
Lyrics/Composition: Ryuujin Kiyoshi  Arrangement: MOSAIC.WAV
もしもね 帰り道
If, on my way home,
グリズリーと出会って
I encountered a grizzly bear,
暗闇で 目が合えば
and our eyes met in the dark,
恐怖で動けないわ
I'd be frozen with fear.
震える 唇で
With trembling lips,
「助けて」って言ったなら
if I said, "Help me,"
あなたは すぐに
would you come
来てくれますか？
to my rescue immediately?
ねぇ 嘘つきで
Hey, don't brush me off
あしらわないで
as a liar.
真実 守って
Protect the truth,
お願い
please.
お邪魔だって 駆けつけてね
Even if it's an intrusion, come running.
一分一秒を 争うのよ
Every second counts.
パジャマに着替える前に
Before you even change into pajamas,
骨まで 食べられちゃうわ
I'll be eaten down to my bones.
裸足だって 駆けつけてね
Even if you're barefoot, come running.
私をお宝 お食い前に
Before my treasure is devoured.
心配で たまらなくって
Feeling overwhelmingly anxious,
走り出して ほしいのね
I want you to start running.
どんな人が嬉しいの？
What kind of person would make you happy?
もしもね 曲がり角
If, at a street corner,
グリズリーとバッタリ
I bumped into a grizzly bear,
物陰で 向き合えば
and we faced off in the shadows,
怖くて 叫べないわ
I'd be too scared to scream.
怯える 左手で
With a frightened left hand,
「助けて」ってメールしたら
if I emailed you, "Help me,"
あなたは すぐに
would you look at it
見てくれますか？
immediately?
ねぇ ほら吹いて
Hey, don't dismiss me
片付けないで
as an exaggerator.
本当の 私を
Believe
信じて
in the real me.
仕事だって 駆けつけてね
Even if you're at work, come running.
何もかもを 投げたって
Even if you throw everything else away.
残業が 終わるまでに
Before my overtime shift ends,
お墓に 埋められちゃうわ
I'll be buried in my grave.
グリズリーに襲われたら
If attacked by a grizzly bear
Eat me.
どこにだって駆けつけてね 私を疑う前に
Run to me anywhere, before doubting me
いてもたってもいられない 飛び出してほしいのです
I can't just sit still, I want you to rush out
どんな人が愛おしいの
What kind of person do you love?
Yeah!
ねえもしもし 大変大変 帰り道にグリズリーがいるの
Hey, hello? It's bad, bad. There's a grizzly on the way home.
助けて 私怖くて一歩も動けないよ 今すぐ来て助けて
Help me, I'm so scared I can't move a step. Come help me right now.
ああ こっち来るよ
Ah, it's coming this way!
私のこと見てる 嫌助けてよ
It's looking at me. No, help me!
あれー
Ah...
ねえ 嘘つきってあしらわないで
Hey, don't brush me off as a liar.
真実なの お願い
It's the truth, please.
雨だって駆けつけてね 一秒を争うのよ
Even in the rain, rush to me. Every second counts.
倍速に着替える前に 骨まで食べられちゃうわ
Before I can change at double speed, I'll be eaten to the bone.
Eat me.
裸足だって駆けつけてね 私を疑う前に
Even barefoot, rush to me, before doubting me.
心配でたまらなくて 走り出してほしいのです
I'm so worried I can't stand it, I want you to start running.
どんな人が嬉しいの
What kind of person makes you happy?
Yeah!
あなたしかいないの
There's no one but you.
シオン先輩！
Shion-senpai!
沙花叉〜！
Sakamata~!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今日主役じゃないですか！
You're the star today!
そうですよ！でも誕生日実はちょっと前なんですけど。
That's right! But my birthday was actually a little while ago.
あっ、そう...
Oh, right...
いや、でも今日もお誕生日ってことでいいよね！
No, but it's fine to call today your birthday too, right!
そうだね！
Right!
なんですかその微妙な反応！
What's with that lukewarm reaction!
ひどいよ！
How mean!
でもこれ見てくださいよ！
But look at this!
ああ、沙花叉たちなかよぴじゃないですか！
Ah, Sakamata and the others are Nakayopi, aren't they!
なかよぴ〜！
Nakayopi~!
なかよぴやめようかな...
Maybe I'll stop the Nakayopi thing...
え？
Eh?
なかよぴ！
Nakayopi!
そうだよ！さっきだって言ってくれてたじゃないですか！
That's right! You were just saying it earlier!
え？じゃあもう一回聞きたいな！
Eh? Then I want to hear it one more time!
あれ！あれ！あれ聞きたいな！
That! That! I want to hear that thing!
あれほしいな！
I want that!
お嫁さんみたいだよね！
It's like being a bride, right!
皆さん、沙花叉が今日からお嫁さんです！
Everyone, Sakamata is a bride starting today!
すみません！足横のみんなごめんね！
Sorry! Sorry to everyone in the Ashiyoko!
シオン先輩の意向だから仕方なく、仕方なくなんですけど！
It's Shion-senpai's wish, so I have no choice, I have no choice!
でもごめん、シオン実は心に決めてる人がいるんだ。
But sorry, Shion actually has someone she's decided on in her heart.
え？誰ですか？
Eh? Who is it?
おかゆって言うんだけどさ。
Her name is Okayu.
ああ、おかゆ先輩か...
Ah, Okayu-senpai...
おかゆ先輩誰にでも言いますよ！
Okayu-senpai says that to everyone!
え？違うよ！シオンだけだよ！
Eh? No! It's just Shion!
いや、違いますよ！
No, you're wrong!
違う！違う！
No! No!
沙花叉はじゃあシオンだけなの？
Then is it just Shion for Sakamata?
沙花叉はシオン先輩だけにしよう！
I'll make it just Shion-senpai for me!
じゃあ沙花叉でいいや！
Then Sakamata is fine!
適当じゃん！やだやだ！
That's so half-hearted! No no!
もっと情愛を！やだ！ひどいよ！
More affection! No! How mean!
え、でも、なんで呼んでくれたんですか？沙花叉じゃないのに。
Eh, but, why did you invite me? Even though I'm not the one.
沙花叉とはさ、コラボはしたことあるけどさ、3Dで並んだことってないじゃん。
I've collaborated with Sakamata before, but we've never stood side-by-side in 3D.
確かに！
True!
だから並びたいなと思って。
So I thought I'd like to stand together.
で、沙花叉は声可愛いから。
And, because Sakamata's voice is cute.
え？
Eh?
声も顔も不器用なところも可愛いから。
Because your voice, your face, and even your clumsiness are cute.
あれ？なんか聞いたことある。どこかのフレーズだな。
Huh? I've heard that somewhere before. It's a phrase from somewhere.
可愛いから、可愛い曲歌いたいと思って。
Because you're cute, I wanted to sing a cute song.
今日このね、「グリズリーに襲われたら」って曲にしました。
So today I chose this song, 'If attacked by a grizzly bear'.
え、でもそれってほぼ心に決めてるんじゃ...わかってないだけですよ。
Eh, but doesn't that mean I'm almost the one... You just don't realize it.
ま、でも沙花叉でもいいや！
Well, but Sakamata is fine!
なんで！「でもいいや」じゃないですよ！
Why! It's not 'is fine'!
じゃあもし本当にグリズリーに襲われたらどうします？シオン先輩。
Then what would you do if you were really attacked by a grizzly? Shion-senpai.
え、シオンがさ、電話したら助けてくれるの？
Eh, if Shion calls you, will you come save me?
いや、もう100%駆けつけますよ！
No, I'll rush there 100%!
いつだって、どうぞどうぞ。
Anytime, please, please.
あの、そういう時じゃなくても全然電話待ってるんで。はい。
Um, even if it's not a time like that, I'm totally waiting for your call. Yes.
いつでも待ってますから。送ってもらってもいいですし。
I'm always waiting. You can send me a message too.
かけてもらっても。今でもいいですよ。
Or call me. Even right now is fine.
グリズリーの役やりましょうか？じゃあちょっとグリズリーになるんで。
Shall I play the grizzly? Okay, I'll be the grizzly for a bit.
シオン先輩のことをちょっとグリズリーとして襲わせていただきますよ！
I'm going to attack Shion-senpai as a grizzly!
はぁ〜、最近本当ついてないな。
Sigh, things really haven't been going my way lately.
うわっ！壁が勝手に割れた！
Whoa! The wall broke on its own!
これじゃシオンが割ったみたいじゃん！
Now it looks like Shion broke it!
あー、どうしよう。また怒られる…
Ah, what should I do? I'm going to get scolded again...
今怒られてきたばっかなのに…
I just got scolded a moment ago...
やぁ、お困りかな？お嬢さん
Hi, are you in trouble, little lady?
どわぁ！おかゆ！？いつからそこに？なんでいんの？
Dowa! Okayu!? Since when were you there? Why are you here?
ボクはちょっと探し物を… ゲフンゲフン
I was just looking for something... *cough*
それより、一体どうしたんだい？
Anyway, what on earth happened?
花瓶が勝手に落ちて割れちゃったの！
The vase just fell and broke on its own!
シオンのせいじゃないのに…
Even though it wasn't Shion's fault...
それは災難だったね。
That was unfortunate.
よしよし、シオンは悪くないよ。
There, there, Shion isn't to blame.
やっぱりおかゆだけはシオンの味方になってくれる！
I knew it, only Okayu would be on Shion's side!
実は今ちょうど、割れた花瓶を元に戻すことだけが存在意義な…
Actually, right now, I have something whose sole purpose of existence is to restore broken vases...
…と思ってるんだけど、お望みならこれで直してあげるよ。
...or so I'm thinking. If you want, I'll fix it with this.
接着剤：割れた花瓶を元に戻す専用
Adhesive: Exclusively for restoring broken vases
マジ！？直して直して！
Really!? Fix it, fix it!
はーい、元通りになったよ。
There, it's back to normal.
すごっ！傷ひとつないんだけど！
Amazing! There's not even a single scratch!
ボクにかかれば、失敗なんて全部なかったことにできちゃうよ。
In my hands, I can make any failure as if it never happened.
失敗をなかったことに…
Making failures as if they never happened...
じ、実はそこの壁に落書きしたのもシオンなんだけど、
A-actually, Shion also did the graffiti on that wall,
油性で書いたから消えなくなっちゃって…
but I used a permanent marker, so it won't come off...
うわぁ、これはひどいね。
Whoa, this is bad.
お願いおかゆ！この落書きもなかったことにして！
Please, Okayu! Make this graffiti never have happened too!
もちろん。今なら特別価格でこのサービスを提供できちゃうよ。
Of course. I can offer this service at a special price right now.
えっ、金取るんすか…？
Eh, you're taking money...?
なんど今なら1万おかゆんポッキリだよ。
Believe it or not, it's just 10,000 Okyayun right now.
でもこれはタイムセール価格だから、あと1分で通常価格の10万おかゆんに…
But this is a time sale price, so in one more minute it'll go to the regular price of 100,000 Okyayun...
えっ！？10万おかゆん！？
Eh!? 100,000 Okyayun!?
は、払います！今すぐ1万おかゆん払います！
I-I'll pay! I'll pay 10,000 Okyayun right now!
壱万おかゆん
10,000 Okyayun
ほら、ご覧の通り。まっさらにしておいたよ。
See, just as you requested. I've made it brand new.
凄すぎます！おかゆさん天才！
Too amazing! Okayu-san is a genius!
かっこいい！もぐもぐして！
So cool! Mogu-mogu me!
ボクのお手頃価格かつ革新的なサービス。お気に召したようで何よりだよ。
My affordable and innovative service. I'm glad you liked it.
あ、じ、実はもう一個ありまして…
Ah, a-actually, there's one more...
昨日Aちゃんのパソコンで勝手に遊んでたら間違えて初期化しちゃって、
Yesterday, I was playing on A-chan's computer without permission and accidentally initialized it,
データとか全部消えちゃったんだよね…
and all the data and everything is gone...
うわぁ、それは難しい仕事だ。100万おかゆんほどかかるね。
Whoa, that's a difficult job. It'll cost about 1,000,000 Okyayun.
え、そ、それは高すぎるんじゃないかな、なんて…
Eh, t-that might be a bit too expensive, maybe...
これは面倒な仕事だよお嬢さん。こんな厄介な仕事をたったの100万おかゆんで
This is a troublesome job, little lady. No other contractor would perfectly
完璧に始末してくれる業者は他にはいないよ。
handle such a mess for just 1,000,000 Okyayun.
まぁ別にボクは困らないから好きにしてくれたまえ。お先に失礼。
Well, I won't be troubled either way, so do as you wish. I'll take my leave.
払います！100万おかゆん払いますから見捨てないでおかゆ様ー！
I'll pay! I'll pay 1,000,000 Okyayun, so don't abandon me, Okayu-sama!
ここをこうして、最後に叩けば。ほら、データも元通り。
Do this here, and give it a final tap. Look, the data is back too.
なんかあんまり変わってない気が…
I feel like it hasn't changed much...
これでお嬢さんの失敗は全部なかったことになった。よかったね。
With this, all of the little lady's failures have never happened. Good for you.
や、やったー！これで何の負い目も感じず表を歩ける。ありがとう、おかゆ！
Y-Yay! Now I can walk outside without feeling any guilt. Thank you, Okayu!
あ、もしもし？Aちゃん？探してた犯人、見つかったよ。
Ah, hello? A-chan? I found the culprit you were looking for.
えっ…？
Eh...?
まいどありー。
Thank you for your business.
よう、なだめ透かされてるお兄ちゃん　なんか辛いことあったんか
Yo, pacified big brother. Did something painful happen?
俺でよけりゃ話してくんない　力になるぜ
If you're okay with me, won't you talk to me? I'll be of help.
一体どんなことがあった　それ引いて話せよ兄弟
What on earth happened? Put that aside and talk, brother.
これやるから元気出しな　噛み花また今度でいいさ
Have this and cheer up. You can pay back the 'flower biting' later.
シャンティ　シャンティ　シャンティ　シャンティ　ハッピー　キャンディ
Chanty, Chanty, Chanty, Chanty, Happy Candy.
ハッピー　ハッピー　ハッピー　キャンディ　マネー　マネー　メニー
Happy, Happy, Happy Candy, Money Money Many.
眠れない夜のチャイナタウン　スベテガナワバリ
Chinatown where you can't sleep. Everything is our territory.
老若男女問わずお客　使い終わったら即連れ去り
Customers of all ages and genders. After use, they're taken away immediately.
今夜も来たのかい　お気に召したかい
Did you come tonight too? Did you like it?
代価はこれくらい　えっ　えっ　えっ
The price is about this much. Eh, eh, eh?
払えないのかい　ならばしょうがない
Can't pay? Well, then there's no choice.
君にピッタリの仕事があるから　こっちに付いてきな
I have a job that's perfect for you, so follow me.
こっちに付いてきな
Follow me.
見上げた空から剥がれた運　しゃがれた看板掲げた女
Luck peeled off from the sky I looked up at. A woman who held up a hoarse sign.
ズタズタナイフで刺される用心　端からアイツもバカどまりだ
Beware of being stabbed with a shredded knife. From the start, he's just an idiot.
イカれてるマザー　チビるぜお前ら納得
Crazy Mother. You guys will pee yourselves, you convinced?
超ちんちろりん　咲かせた果て猛進猛進　奏でたまえ
Super Chinchirorin. In the end it bloomed, rush rush, please play.
黙れ座れ黙れや
Shut up, sit down, shut up.
殴れ殴れ殴れや
Hit it, hit it, hit it.
縛れ縛れ縛れや
Tie it up, tie it up, tie it up.
バラせバラせバラせや
Expose it, expose it, expose it.
今夜はあとどうだい　お気に召したかい
How's the rest of tonight? Did you like it?
代価はこれくらい
The price is about this much.
ギ、ギ...
Gi, gi...
シャンティが招待。
Shanty invites you.
そんな暇なく転がすビジネス。
No time for that, just roll the business.
どっちを向いてんだ？
Where are you looking?
やけに慣れてるその情緒。
You're unusually used to those emotions.
これで避ければ話してくんない？
If you avoid it like this, won't you talk to me?
シオン、誕生日おめでとー！
Shion, happy birthday!
ありがとう、おかゆー！
Thank you, Okayu!
いや、僕たちのシャンティよすぎないか？
Man, isn't our 'Shanty' just too good?
いや、本当に良かった。
Yeah, it was really great.
ねー。
Right?
シャンティに関してはさ、シャンティおかゆとさ、
As for 'Shanty', with Okayu-chan...
50年前くらいから一緒に歌いたいって言ってたのよ。
I've been saying I wanted to sing it with you since about 50 years ago.
50年前から言ってたのがようやく今日、実を結びました。
What we've been saying for 50 years finally came to fruition today.
そうだよ。みんな50年前のあのお願いが叶った今。
That's right. Everyone, that wish from 50 years ago has come true now.
そうだよ。おめでとう本当に。
Yeah. Congratulations, really.
ありがとう本当に。
Thank you, really.
え、ちなみに50年前、何で僕と一緒にシャンティ歌いたかったの？
By the way, why did you want to sing 'Shanty' with me 50 years ago?
え、なんか、やっぱりかっこいい曲じゃんか。
Well, it's a cool song, you know?
そうだね。
True.
かっこよく一緒に歌いたいなと思って、おかゆかっこいいからさ。
I thought I wanted to sing it coolly together, because Okayu is cool.
えー、ありがとうシオン。チュしてあげよっか。
Aw, thanks Shion. Should I give you a kiss?
え、してくれるの？
Wait, you will?
明日に。
Tomorrow.
明日ね。明日ね。
Tomorrow, huh? Tomorrow.
そうだよね。
Right.
でもさ、シャンティは確かにかっこいい感じだったけどさ、
But, while 'Shanty' was definitely cool...
シオン冒頭の何？導入に入ってたアニメでお金取られてなかった？
Shion, in that anime intro at the beginning, weren't you having money taken from you?
なんかさ、そう、おかゆに取られたんだよね。
Like, yeah, Okayu took it from me.
うん。取られてなかなか他人事だけど、そうおかゆに取られたんだよね。
Yeah. It was like someone else's problem, but yeah, Okayu took it.
なんか、僕にお金取られてたみたいだったけどさ、
It looked like I was taking money from you, but...
111万オカ円ね。
1,110,000 Oka-yen.
オカ円取られてたけどさ。
I had Oka-yen taken from me.
ま、でもさ、おかゆが全部直してくれたじゃん。
Well, but Okayu fixed everything, right?
なかったことにしてくれ...あ、でも待って、通報されたしそういえば。
Like it never happened... Oh wait, I was reported to the police come to think of it.
よかったシオンが能天気で。
Good thing Shion is so carefree.
おかゆー！
Okayu!
お、そういえばほら見て。
Oh, by the way, look at this.
なに？
What?
めっちゃ可愛くない？あのイラスト。
Isn't that illustration super cute?
ねえねえ。あれ結婚指輪かな。
Hey, hey. Are those wedding rings?
え、でもあれ人差し指についてるみたいだけど。
Eh, but it looks like they're on the index fingers.
え、でもほら、そういう、そういうのもあるじゃん、結婚指輪。
But you know, there are wedding rings like that too.
ま、確かに。シオンは人差し指くらいがちょうどいいと思う。
Well, true. I think index fingers are just right for Shion.
そうだよね。だってもうないじゃんね。
Right. Because there are no rules...
この指に絶対つけなきゃいけないなんて多分ない。
That you absolutely HAVE to wear it on this finger.
好きな指でいいじゃんね。
Any finger you like is fine.
そうだね。
Yeah.
確かに。結婚指輪なんだ。
True. So it IS a wedding ring.
うん。そういうことにしとこうかな。
Yeah. Let's go with that.
いや、可愛いな、すごい。
Wow, it's so cute.
可愛い。
Cute.
ねえ、ネックレスもつけちゃってさ。
Hey, we're even wearing necklaces.
本当だよ、かっこいい。遊戯王みたいな感じでいいよね、すごく。
Really, it's cool. It's got that Yu-Gi-Oh vibe, which is great.
ねえ、かっこいい。
Yeah, cool.
すごいよ。こうやってる。
Amazing. They're posing like this.
こうやってね。
Like this.
いや、かっこいいこれ。みんなスクショタイムだよ。
Wow, this is cool. Everyone, it's screenshot time.
かっこいいね。
So cool.
ま、何はともあれシオン、本当にお誕生日おめでとう。
Anyway, Shion, happy birthday.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
じゃあ僕は100万年後も一緒にいてくれる？
Then, will you stay with me for the next million years?
もちろんだよ、シオン。
Of course, Shion.
そうだよね。明日結婚しよーね。
I knew it. Let's get married tomorrow.
うん、明日ね。
Yeah, tomorrow.
うーん、なんか声が聞こえる...
Mmm, I hear a voice...
シオンちゃん起きて！
Shion-chan, wake up!
眠っちゃだめ！
Don't fall asleep!
痛いわ！何してんの、ねねち！
That hurts! What are you doing, Nene-chi!
よかった。今寝たら漏れなく死ぬよ。
Thank goodness. If you fall asleep now, you'll definitely die.
なにここ寒！吹雪いてんだけど！
What is this place? It's so cold! There's a blizzard!
ここは宇宙最高峰の標高を誇るネネネスト！
This is Nene-st, boasting the highest altitude in the universe!
私たちは人類の希望を背負って、この山の頂を制するためにやってきた。
We've come to conquer the summit of this mountain, carrying the hopes of humanity.
なにこれ収録始まってる？
What is this? Has the recording started?
しかし、数時間にわたる吹雪にさらされ絶体絶命。
However, exposed to a blizzard for several hours, we're in a desperate situation.
どんどん低下する体温を保つため、二人は抱きしめ合うのだった。
To maintain their dropping body temperatures, the two embraced each other.
は？
Huh?
うわあ、骨があ！
Whoa, my bones!
シオン、この挑戦が終わったら結婚しよう。
Shion, let's get married when this challenge is over.
するか！
As if!
あれ、何ここ？野球場？
Huh, what is this place? A baseball field?
かっとばせー、ねねち！
Knock it out of the park, Nene-chi!
自分でも言ってる。
She's saying it herself.
ツーアウト満塁。ホームランなら一発逆転、三振で試合即終了。
Two outs, bases loaded. A home run means a grand slam comeback, a strikeout ends the game immediately.
俺たちの青春がこの打席にかかってる！
Our youth depends on this at-bat!
シオン野球知らんから何言ってんのかちょっと分かんない。
Shion doesn't know baseball, so I don't really know what you're talking about.
マネージャー！
Manager!
うわ、シオンマネージャーなの？
Whoa, is Shion the manager?
ここでホームランを打ったら、おーたんと付き合ってくれー！
If I hit a home run here, go out with O-tan!
お断りします！
I decline!
かっきーん！
Crack!
あー、なんか変な夢見た気がするんだけど。
Ah, I feel like I just had a weird dream.
頭痛い。
My head hurts.
お、ちょうどいいところに水置いてあんじゃん。
Oh, there's some water in just the right place.
ぷはー！効くー！
Phew! That hits the spot!
あら、飲んだね、シオンちゃん。
Oh, you drank it, Shion-chan.
お、ねねち、いつの間に！
Whoa, Nene-chi, since when?!
グビッといっちゃったね、シオンちゃん。
You drank it all down, Shion-chan.
思いっきり飲んだけど、ねねち、まさかシオンに毒を...！
I drank it all, but Nene-chi, did you put poison in my...?!
くっくっく、くっくでシオンちゃんに質問です！
He-he-he, time for a question for Shion-chan!
なんか始まった。
Here we go again.
ズバリ！ホロライブメンバーの中で恋人にしたいのはだーれ！
Out of all the Hololive members, who would you want as a lover?!
おかゆ。
Okayu.
ちがーう！
Wrong!
さっきから何やってんの？
What have you been doing this whole time?
つぎぶし効果もホフブラン整形もホルゲシェールも効かないってどういうこと！
Why didn't the Tsugibushi-effect, Hofubran-seikei, or the Horuge-shieru work?!
お薬入れたんかお前！
Did you put drugs in there?!
あとでおかゆ先輩にどんな惚れ薬使ってるのか聞かないと。
I'll have to ask Okayu-senpai later what kind of love potion she uses.
おかゆが惚れ薬みたいなもんなんだよ。
Okayu herself is basically a love potion.
やだー！ねねもシオンちゃん惚れさせたい！うわー！
No! Nene wants to make Shion-chan fall for her too! Argh!
え、ていうかさ、ねねちそんなにシオンのこと好きだったの？
Wait, Nene-chi, do you actually like me that much?
いや、次の収録まで暇だったから遊んでただけー！
No, I was just bored before the next recording and was just playing around!
ほい、しおよー！
Take that! Shio-yoo!
だいしゅきだいしゅき
Daisuki Daisuki
Watch out Get you 熱烈 Emotion
シュキシュキではじけた Be my Roulette
Watch out, Get you, passionate emotion
Pop with shuki-shuki, be my roulette
Go to start トキトキ Get it! 急、急、急、急でも
Go to start, get it with excitement! Even if it's sudden
Thank you Thank you ときめきな Q
1ミリの隙間に Diving
Thank you, thank you, heart-pounding Q
Diving into a 1mm gap
Love trap 全部恋文 Up! 急、急、急、急でも
Love trap, all love letters up! Even if it's sudden
だって今日はゴッドメンタル
勇ましきチャレンジャー
Because today I have god-level mental strength
A brave challenger
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
だいしゅきだいしゅき 1 2 3 はい！
Just a little sentimental
Daisuki daisuki 1 2 3, go!
まみむめもめもめも見れないの
たちつてとてとてと手が震えて
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, I can't look at you
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to, my hands are shaking
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
もっときゅきゅきゅきゅと強制 Love
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
More and more, forced love
あのね クリオネ 透けてるハート
でもね この胸 見透かさないで
You know, like a sea angel, a transparent heart
But hey, don't see through this heart of mine
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
If it's not me, you're finished
Watch out Get you 見つけちゃった中
シュキシュキでカラフル Cutie pie
Watch out, Get you, I found it inside
Pop with shuki-shuki, colorful cutie pie
Roulette ちょっとドッポイ Thank you!
C-I-A C-I-A でも
Roulette, a bit dandy, thank you!
Even if it's C-I-A, C-I-A
だって今日はまとめて
うわさしきチャレンジャー
Because today, all together
The rumored challenger
ハート書いたオートメーション
だいしゅきだいしゅき 1 2 3 はい！
Automation with a heart drawn
Daisuki daisuki 1 2 3, go!
まみむめもめもめも見せてほしいの
なにぬねのねのねの恋の子猫と
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, I want you to show me
Na-ni-nu-ne-no, with a kitten in love
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
もっとききききしゅきょーせー Love
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
More and more, forced love
あのね マリオネット 操らな Lady
でもね それもね 悪くはないね
You know, like a marionette, a controlled lady
But hey, that's not too bad either
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
If it's not me, you're finished
フレンドリーなフリして
周波数を逃さないで
Pretending to be friendly
Don't miss the frequency
言わつきの魅惑のリップ
リアルになる未来
Bewitching lips with stories to tell
A future that becomes real
まみむめもめもめも見れないの
たちつてとてとてと手が震えて
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, I can't look at you
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to, my hands are shaking
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
もっときゅきゅきゅきゅと強制 Love
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
More and more, forced love
あのね クリオネ 透けてるハート
でもね この胸 見透かさないで
You know, like a sea angel, a transparent heart
But hey, don't see through this heart of mine
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
If it's not me, you're finished
まみむめもめもめも見れないの
たちつてとてとてと手が震えて
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, I can't look at you
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to, my hands are shaking
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
もっときゅきゅきゅきゅと強制 Love
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
More and more, forced love
あのね クリオネ 透けてるハート
でもね この胸 見透かさないで
You know, like a sea angel, a transparent heart
But hey, don't see through this heart of mine
だいしゅきゅ だいしゅきになれ
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
Dai-shukyu, fall for me
If it's not me, you're finished
シオンちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Shion-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
な、ちょっと遅めだね。
It's a bit late, though.
そうだよ、ちょっと遅くなっちゃった。
Yeah, it's gotten a bit late.
ちょっと遅くなっちゃったか。ちょっとお待たせ。
Gotten a bit late, huh? Sorry to keep you waiting.
久しぶりのマブダチでーす！
It's our first time together in a while as besties!
すごい揃った、嘘。
That was so perfectly in sync! No way.
ま、マブダチだし当たり前か。
Well, we're besties, so of course.
当たり前だよなぁ。
Of course!
そうだよ、え、でもさ、二人で3D初めてらしいよ。
Right! But you know, it's our first time in 3D together.
そんなことある？マブ...マブなのに。
Is that even possible? Even though we're besties?
おかしいなぁ。
It's strange, right?
え、え、初めてとかそんなわけ...
Was it really the first time? There's no way...
ないよね？
...right?
ない、ない、ない。
No, no, no.
なんか初めてな気がするだけ。
Maybe it just feels like the first time?
そういうことか、記憶喪失だわ。
Maybe it's memory loss?
え、ちょっと忘れ...忘れないでー！
Wait, don't forget!
もう嫌だー！
Oh no!
忘れないでよ、マブのこと。
Don't forget about your bestie!
ちょっとそういえば後ろの絵、可愛すぎな！
By the way, the illustration behind us is so cute!
めちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
ハートしてる。
They're making a heart.
ハートしてるわ。すいちゃん腹エッチだなぁ。
They are. Sui-chan, your belly is so sexy.
エッチ？ねねおじ？
Sexy? Nene-oji?
ねねおじですか？
Is it Nene-oji?
あ、後ろも素敵だよ、こっちの本体の後ろも。
Look, the back of the real us is also nice.
ちょっと嫌だ、やめてよー！
Wait, stop!
ちょっと恥ずかしい。
Wait, I'm embarrassed!
でもさ、シオンちゃん、ねねさ、シオンちゃんと付き合いたいから！
But you know, Shion-chan, Nene wants to date Shion-chan!
やっぱりねねちって、シオンのこと、もしかして、す、す、好きなの？
I knew it, Nene, do you... l-l-love Shion?
そうでもないよ。
Not really.
ディックス！
Dicks!
べぇー！
Ugh!
あー、今日も疲れ...
Man, I'm tired today too...
すいちゃん、何してんの？
Sui-chan, what are you doing?
なーてーぼーくーわーほーしーだーかーらー
Because I'm a shooting star...
あ、シオンちゃん。こんにちは。
Oh, Shion-chan. Hello.
こ、こんにちは、どうしたの？
Hello, what's wrong?
最近満たされない気持ちが大きくなって、
Lately, the feeling of not being fulfilled has grown so much,
ついに感情を失ってしまったの。
that I've finally lost my emotions.
え、可哀想。
Eh? Poor thing.
もう何もする気が起きなくて、
I don't feel like doing anything anymore, so
こうして床に突っ伏してることが自分の使命だと思えてきた。
I've started to think it's my mission to just lie face down on the floor like this.
ずっとその状態で話すのやめて！
Stop talking while in that state!
アニメーション組む人も私がずっとこのままでいたほうが楽だろうし。
I'm sure the animators would find it easier if I just stayed like this too.
すいちゃん、こら！
Sui-chan, cut it out!
美味しいもの食べれば気分も上がってくるって！
If you eat something delicious, your mood will improve!
ほら、買ってきたから一緒に食べよう。
Look, I bought some, so let's eat together!
すみません、いただきます。
Pardon me. Let's eat.
敬語！？
Polite speech!?
だめだ。美味しいはずなのに全然感情が動かない。
It's no use. It should be delicious, but my heart doesn't move at all.
シオンの分は！？
What about Shion's share!?
やはり食事では私の心を動かすことができない。
As expected, food cannot move my heart.
嫌いな食べ物もあるし。
And I hate these ingredients too.
野菜だけ綺麗に残しやがって！
You left only the vegetables so perfectly!
次はファンレターを読おう！
Next, let's read fan letters!
ほら、こんなに大きなダンボールにいっぱい来てる！
Look, so many came in this huge cardboard box!
ありがたい限りです。
I am truly grateful.
姿勢よ！
Your posture!?
ほら見てすいちゃん、歌がとっても好きですってメッセージ来てるよ！
Look Sui-chan, here's a message saying they love your singing!
う、うた？
S... singing?
そうだよ！すいちゃんには歌があるじゃん！自分を信じて！
That's right! Sui-chan, you have your singing! Believe in yourself!
そうか。私には歌があるんだ。
I see. I have my singing.
野菜が食べれないところ以外は全部大好きです。
"I love everything about you except the fact that you can't eat vegetables."
以外...
Except...
ネガティブに捉えてそう。
She's taking it negatively!
すいちゃんはー！今日も可愛いいいいいいいい！
Sui-chan is— today too, cuuuuuuute!
怖い怖い怖い怖い！すいちゃんバグらないで！
Scary, scary, scary, scary! Sui-chan, don't bug out!
すいちゃんは偏食だけど可愛い！
Sui-chan is a picky eater but cute!
あー、引きずってる。
Ah, she's dragging herself.
仕方ない、シオン秘蔵の超高級素材を使用して作った、
It can't be helped. Using Shion's secret, ultra-high-grade ingredients,
この魔法薬をあげよう。
I'll give you this magic potion.
何でそんな魔女みたいなこと？
Why are you acting like a witch?
魔女だよ！これは一瓶飲めばなんでも食べれるようになる魔法の薬。
I am a witch! This is a magic medicine that lets you eat anything after drinking one bottle.
人が飲んでいい色してない。
It's not a color humans should drink.
ちょっと苦いけど、作るのにシオンの月収レベルのお金がかかってるから、
It's a bit bitter, but it cost Shion as much as her monthly salary to make,
大事に飲んで！
so drink it carefully!
いや、ちょっ...
Wait, hey...
はい！一気！一気！一気！
Okay! Chug! Chug! Chug!
うわぁー！シオンの月収がー！
Whoa! My monthly salary!
何吐いてんだこの！
What are you vomiting, you!?
あんなもん飲めるか！
Like I could drink something like that!
こわ！
Scary!
食べなくちゃ 食べなくちゃ
I have to eat, I have to eat
嫌なことは忘れさせて
Make me forget the bad things
行かないでね 行かないで
Don't go, please don't go
君の体 本当 心臓
Your body, truly, your heart
愛 愛 I love you too
Love, love, I love you too
愛 愛 I hate you
Love, love, I hate you
君のすべてが 私ならいいのに
If only everything about you were mine
満たされない 満たされない
I'm not fulfilled, I'm not fulfilled
満たされないのはフィーリング
It's the feeling that isn't fulfilled
愛されたい 愛されたい
I want to be loved, I want to be loved
愛されたいのは君 ずっと
The one who wants to be loved is you, forever
はかなくちゃ もう はかなくちゃ
I have to throw it up, already, I have to
冷め冷め 泣いても終点だ
Being cold and crying, it's the end of the line
可愛くない ああ 可愛くない
I'm not cute, ah, I'm not cute
可愛くないから消えたい
I want to disappear because I'm not cute
冤罪解放中 もう暗渠 調査中
Freeing from false accusations, exploring culverts
私のすべてが あの子ならいいのに
If only everything about me were that girl
満たされない 満たされない
I'm not fulfilled, I'm not fulfilled
満たされないのはフィーリング
It's the feeling that isn't fulfilled
理解されない 理解されたい
Not being understood, wanting to be understood
理解されないのは地球規模
Being misunderstood on a global scale
満たされたい 満たされたい
I want to be fulfilled, I want to be fulfilled
満たされたいから嫌い
I hate you because I want to be fulfilled
愛されたい 愛されたい
I want to be loved, I want to be loved
愛されたいのは地球規模
Wanting to be loved on a global scale
わあー！ わあー！
Waaa! Waaa!
ちょっとしっとりだったけど
It was a bit mellow, but...
いえーい！
Yay!
しーたんおめでとう！
Shi-tan, congratulations!
ありがとうすいちゃん！来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you, Sui-chan! Thank you for coming!
しーたんなんて初めて呼んだ
I've never called you "Shi-tan" before.
初めて呼ばれた
It's the first time I've been called that!
First time being called that.
えっ、なんで、さっき呼んでくれたの？
Eh, why did you call me that just now?
えっ、すいちゃん、今日は...
Eh, Sui-chan, today...
今日ゲストで、おかゆと...
Today's guests, Okayu and...
おかゆ以外、みんなあの、3Dで
Everyone except Okayu, well,
二人に並ぶの初めてだったの
it was the first time standing together in 3D.
えっ、初めてじゃん確かに
Eh, it is our first time, actually.
そうなんだよ、うちら初めてじゃん
That's right, it's our first time!
こんにちは。こんにちは、はじめまして。
Hello. Hello, nice to meet you.
えっちっちゃい
Oh, you're tiny.
バカにしてる？
Are you making fun of me?
バカにしてる
You're making fun of me.
でもめっちゃ嬉しかった呼んでもらえて
But I was really happy to be invited.
えっ本当に？
Eh, really?
そう、だってしおんとなかなかね、
Yeah, because with Shion,
会うこともね、そんなにないしさ
we don't really have many chances to meet.
そうなんだよね。今まで、そう
That's true. Until now, yeah,
ライブでちょっと挨拶したりとかくらいだったんだよね
it was just greeting each other a bit at lives.
最近だとね、クリスマスパーティーね
Recently, there was the Christmas party.
呼びましたよ！
I invited you!
めっちゃ嬉しかった呼んでくれて
I was so happy you invited me.
めっちゃ嬉しかったよね
It was really happy, wasn't it?
なんかさ、あのさ、どこかからさ、
You know, well, from somewhere,
しおんちゃんが私のこと気になってるって...
I heard Shion-chan was interested in me...
あ、出た。どこ、どこそれ。どこから聞いたの
Ah, there it is! Where, where's that? Where'd you hear it?
どこから聞いたの
Where did you hear that from?
気になってんなーと思って。めっちゃ嬉しいけど、
I thought, "She's interested, huh." I'm really happy, but
実際どうなんですか？
how is it actually?
え、気になってた
Eh, I was interested.
嘘でしょ？ すごい。
No way? Amazing.
ここでさ「別に気になってはない」って言われたらおもろいけど
It would be funny if you said "I'm not particularly interested."
正直、全然言いたいんだけど
To be honest, I really want to say it, but...
えっなんでこの曲選んだの？
Eh, why did you choose this song?
えっすいちゃんとは、えっすいちゃんってめちゃめちゃ歌が上手くて
Eh, with Sui-chan... Sui-chan is just so good at singing,
本当隣に並ぶのもちょっと恐れ多いぐらい歌が上手くて
I'm almost intimidated to stand next to her, she's that good.
そんな！
Not at all!
えっそう、だから、えっかっこよすぎたら私ついていけないと思って
Yeah, so, I thought if it was too cool, I wouldn't be able to keep up.
綺麗な曲、綺麗な曲ならギリギリいけると思ったけど、
I thought with a beautiful song, I could barely manage, but...
すいちゃんが上手すぎたんだよね
Sui-chan was just too good, wasn't she?
そんなことないですよ
That's not true!
もうこの「食虫植物」みたいな曲調はもうしーたんの...
This "Insectivorous Plant" kind of melody is totally Shi-tan's...
本当？ 合ってる？
Really? Does it fit?
独壇場ですよ
It's your specialty.
似合ってた？
Did it suit me?
めっちゃ似合ってた
It suited you so much.
やったー。嬉しい。すいちゃんに褒められるの嬉しいな
Yay! I'm happy. I'm happy to be praised by Sui-chan.
えへへ、みんな！
Ehe-he, everyone!
ママみたい
Like a mother.
ママ？
Mother?
お母さんに褒められてるみたい。どんどん後ろに下がっちゃって
It's like being praised by my mother. You're backing away more and more.
お恥ずかしい
I'm embarrassed.
なんか恥ずかしいって気持ちになっちゃうかもしれない。そう
I might just start feeling embarrassed. Yeah.
あとなんか、めっちゃ嬉しかった
And also, I was really happy.
あの、楽曲のイラストもね、こちら
Um, the illustration for the song, too, this one...
そう、しおんちゃん...
Right, Shion-chan...
も用意してくれたんですけど、
prepared this for us,
どうですか感想？
what are your thoughts?
え、コンセプトは？
Wait, what's the concept?
コンセプト？
Concept?
コンセプトは、食虫植物。
The concept is... a carnivorous plant.
わかるよ、食虫植物。
I get it, a carnivorous plant.
こうやってやってる。
Like this.
ねえ、こっち、食べられそうだもん。
See, this side, looks like I could be eaten.
シオンに。
By Shion.
そうそう。
Exactly.
イエーイ。
Yay.
なんかさ、ヤンデレ感あるよね。
It's got that yandere vibe, doesn't it?
あるね。
It does.
狙ってるよ、多分。
I'm aiming for it, probably.
めちゃめちゃ狙われてるもん、
I'm definitely being targeted,
命狙ってるよね。
you're aiming for my life.
これ完全にさ、催眠かけられた後なんだもん。
This is totally after I've been hypnotized.
え、エッチってことあれ？
Wait, does that mean it's lewd?
はい、終わり！
Okay, that's enough!
That's enough!
はい、ということで、
Alright, well,
シオンちゃんおめでとうございました！
congratulations, Shion-chan!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
また一緒に歌おうね。
Let's sing together again.
歌おう！
Let's!
ありがとう、すいちゃん。
Thanks, Sui-chan.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
A ray of light illuminating this chaotic Reiwa-era internet
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing smiles to the otaku drifting in the electronic sea
未来の平和をお約束
Promising peace for the future
躁鬱だけどまかせとけ
I'm manic-depressive, but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル　ただいま降臨
The Internet Angel has now descended
INTERNET OVERDOSE
社会をやめろ　家族をやめろ
Quit society, quit your family
人間関係をやめろ
Quit all your relationships
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Bask in the pale light of a dim room right now
大丈夫　こわかったこと全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything that scared you
現実よりも crazy for you
Even more than reality, I'm crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
The internet's information overload is driving me mad
今助けてあげるよ　ダーリン　ダーリン
I'll save you now, darling, darling
ウソはウソと見抜けるし
I can see through lies as lies
この愛は暴走しちゃうし
And this love is running wild
壊れてしまうけど
Even if I end up broken
考えなくていいんだよ
You don't have to think about anything
もうすぐ楽になるから
It'll be easy soon
脳内に乱反射する poison radio
Poison radio reflecting wildly in my brain
麻薬より甘いよ
It's sweeter than drugs
いいね　よくないね
Like it, dislike it
キミにとっては毒だね
It's poison for you, isn't it?
いいね　よくないね
Like it, dislike it
それでも飲むんだね
But you drink it anyway
いいね　よくないね
Like it, dislike it
二人のヒミツだね
It's our little secret
わたしだけ見ててね
Just keep your eyes on me
まるで天使のように微笑む
Smiling just like an angel
強めの幻覚インターネット・ガール
An intense hallucinogenic Internet Girl
そして悪魔みたいにささやく
And whispering like a devil
アナタだけのデパス　NEEDY NEEDY
Your very own Depas, NEEDY NEEDY
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
Shallow sleep and an overdose of the desire for approval
脳天直撃するわたしたちだけの宗教と光
A religion and light hitting our brains directly
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
A love living more intensely than ethics, eroding even the universe
何度も送られる毒電波を　優しさだけで包んで
Wrap the toxic radio waves sent again and again in nothing but kindness
逆さまのコンピューターと断片的なカウンセリング
An upside-down computer and fragmentary counseling
きらめく屋上で奏でた　夢見心地の旋律
A dreamlike melody played on a sparkling rooftop
夕暮れ時にさよならの演習をして
Practicing saying goodbye at twilight
壊して愛しているって狂って狂って狂って甘く狂わせて
Break me, say you love me, drive me mad, drive me mad, drive me mad, sweetly drive me mad
ゆらぎ始める世界　曖昧になる風景
A world beginning to sway, a landscape becoming blurred
アナタだけが映っているメモリー
A memory where only you are reflected
神様なんていないよ
There is no God
このふざけたインターネットを七色のサイケデリック
Turn this ridiculous internet into a seven-colored psychedelic
SNSという瓶詰地獄に救済を
Bringing salvation to the bottled hell known as SNS
過去の歴史は見ないフリ
Pretending not to see the history of the past
あなたのためならすぐさまに
If it's for you, then immediately
インターネット・エンジェル　かわいく参上
The Internet Angel arrives cutely
まるで天使のように抱きつく
Clinging to you just like an angel
強めの幻覚インターネット・ガール
An intense hallucinogenic Internet Girl
そして悪魔みたいにキスする
And kissing just like a devil
アナタだけの2D　エンジェル
Your very own 2D Angel
ANGEL ANGEL ANGEL
はーい！というわけで、インターネット・オーバードーズでしたー！
Hi! So, that was Internet Overdose!
めちゃめちゃね、これも...
This one too, it was really...
可愛い演出になってたんじゃないかなって思います。
I think it turned out to be a cute production.
見てましたか？ちゃんと。
Were you watching closely?
あ、ちょっと疲れちゃった。
Ah, I'm a bit tired.
はい。というわけでね、どうでしたか？ここまでのライブは。
Alright. So, how has the live been so far?
みんな楽しんでくれましたか？
Did everyone enjoy themselves?
そう。でね、言い忘れちゃったんですけど、ゲストライブの前に
Right. And, I forgot to mention, before the guest live...
なんか、なんかあったでしょ？謎の。何、何あれ？
Something... something happened, right? Something mysterious. What was that?
急に「何あれ？」ってそうなったでしょ？みんな多分。
Suddenly you were like, "What's that?", right? Everyone, probably.
そう、実はですね、あのゲストライブの前にMMDの動画を
So, actually, before that guest live, we showed an MMD video...
アニメ動画をちょっと作って差し込んでもらいました。
An anime video we made and had inserted.
見ましたか？
Did you see it?
曲の内容に寄せてる感じになってたんですけど。
It was made to match the content of the song.
面白かったですか？
Was it interesting?
面白かったですよね？面白かったんだよね？
It was interesting, wasn't it? It was, wasn't it?
はい。というわけでね、そんな感じで...
Alright. So, with that said...
え！あ！あれは！
Eh! Ah! That is!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
MAISON des
紫咲シオン
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
MAISON des
Murasaki Shion
何、何だあれ！というわけで、えっと、この後ですね、配信が終了後に
What... what's that! So, well, after this, once the stream ends...
プレミア公開します！イエーイ！
I'll be doing a Premiere! Yay!
「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」の歌ってみたを作りました！
I've made a cover of "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous"!
というわけで配信終わってすぐにプレミア公開するので
So, right after the stream, I'll be premiering it...
これも見てね！
So watch this too!
はい。というわけで、この後の曲は...
Alright. So, the next song is...
「シャンデリア」です。聞いてね！
..."Chandelier". Please listen!
叶わないないないの妬みそう
An un-un-unattainable jealousy
シャンデリア
作詞・作曲・編曲：Kanaria
Chandelier
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Kanaria
行き場ない情熱苦しそう
A misplaced, painful passion
君からもらって洒落ならららら
Getting it from you, it's no joke-la-la-la-la
衝動からはあらがえないわ
I can't resist the impulse
あとちょっとそっとずっとええと秘密言は
Just a little more, softly, forever, um, secrets are...
譲れないわ叶わないわ
I can't give them up, they're unattainable
あとちょっとの距離イメージ秘密言は
Just a little more distance, imagery, secrets are...
飾らないわ忘れないわ
I won't dress them up, I won't forget them
まだまだラキラキハッピだらだらくをきたらウェーイ
Still, lucky-lucky happy, idling in the space, yay!
なら一な去ってまた一なねお願いぎゅっとハグして
So leave one and another one, please give me a tight hug
ラキラキハッピはたまたくをきてマイウェーイ
Lucky-lucky happy, or coming to the space, my way
ならお願い聞いてあてまがいんでしょ
Then listen to my wish, it's just a placeholder, right?
叶わないないないの妬みそう
An un-un-unattainable jealousy
行き場ない情熱痛みも
A misplaced passion, and the pain too
君から奪って洒落ならららら
Taking it from you, it's no joke-la-la-la-la
衝動からは逃げられないわ
I can't escape from the impulse
ハッピハッピハッピまたまたくをむいてらウェーイ
Happy happy happy, looking towards the space again, yay!
なら一な去ってまた一なねお願いぎゅっとラブリーナ
So leave one and another one, please give me a tight hug, lovely-na
ラキラキハッピまだまだあいにあいにあいにあいにあいに
Lucky-lucky happy, still love-love-love-love-love
お願い聞いてはなはたしでしょ
Then listen to my wish, it's profound, right?
叶わないないないの妬みそう
An un-un-unattainable jealousy
行き場ない情熱痛みと
A misplaced passion, and the pain
君からもらって洒落ならららら
Getting it from you, it's no joke-la-la-la-la
衝動からはあらがえないわ
I can't resist the impulse
心の底まで近づいてまだ
Getting close to the bottom of my heart, still...
相対する声フルデザイア
Opposing voices, full desire
心の底まで二人で近づいてほら
Getting close to the bottom of our hearts together, see?
衝動からはあらがえないわ
I can't resist the impulse